<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reference on qri</title>
    <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reference on qri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qri.io/docs/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>dataset</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/dataset/</guid>
      <description>Dataset A Dataset is a document for describing &amp;amp; storing structured data. Dataset documents are designed to satisfy the FAIR principle of being Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, and Reproducible, in relation to other dataset documents, and related-but-separate technologies such as data catalogs, HTTP API&amp;rsquo;s, and data package formats Datasets are designed to be stored and distributed on content-addressed (identify-by-hash) systems The dataset document definition is built from a research-first principle, valuing direct interoperability with existing standards over novel definitions or specifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>glossary</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/glossary/</guid>
      <description>Qri is filled with all sorts of weird words and terrible acronyms. This page is to make them less terrible.
the Distributed Web Ugh, ok this is a biggie.
Dataset IPFS IPFS stands for the inteplanatary file system, which is a distributed web protocol. IPFS is the default network qri uses to store &amp;amp; publish datasets.
qri I know, I&amp;rsquo;m so sorry for doing this to the world, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping we can all learn to see &amp;ldquo;qri&amp;rdquo; and say &amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>html templates</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/html_templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/html_templates/</guid>
      <description> HTML Templates </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>skylark transformations</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/skylark_syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/skylark_syntax/</guid>
      <description>Skylark Syntax Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is about datasets. Transformions are repeatable scripts for generating a dataset. Skylark is a scripting langauge from Google that feels a lot like python. This package implements skylark as a transformation syntax. Skylark tranformations are about as close as one can get to the full power of a programming language as a transformation syntax. Often you need this degree of control to generate a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>