<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reference on qri</title>
    <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reference on qri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qri.io/docs/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlark Std. Library</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlib/</guid>
      <description>Starlark Standard Library All qri transforms have access to &amp;ldquo;starlib&amp;rdquo;, a community-driven project to bring a standard library to the starlark programming dialect. We here at Qri need a standard library, and we thought it might benefit others to structure this library in a reusable way. We are a little biased towards our needs, and will be shaping the library primarily toward&amp;rsquo;s Qri&amp;rsquo;s use case.
qri and dataset modules In Qri two &amp;ldquo;nonstandard&amp;rdquo; modules specific to qri are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI commands</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/cli_commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/cli_commands/</guid>
      <description>Qri CLI command line reference Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is a global dataset version control system on the distributed web.
   Command Description     qri add Add a dataset from another peer   qri body Get the body of a dataset   qri config Get and set local configuration information   qri connect Connect to the distributed web by spinning up a Qri node   qri diff Compare differences between two datasets   qri export Copy datasets to your local filenamesystem   qri get Get elements of qri datasets   qri info Show summarized description of a dataset   qri list Show a list of datasets   qri log Show log of dataset history   qri peers Commands for working with peers   qri publish Make your dataset available on the registry and to your connected peers   qri registry Commands for working with a qri registry   qri remove Remove a dataset from your local repository   qri rename Change the name of a dataset   qri render Execute a template against a dataset   qri save Create a new dataset or save changes to an existing dataset   qri search Search qri   qri setup Initialize qri and IPFS repositories, provision a new qri ID   qri use Select datasets for use with the qri get command   qri validate Show schema validation errors   qri version Print the version number</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataset</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/dataset/</guid>
      <description>Dataset A Dataset is a document for describing &amp;amp; storing structured data. Dataset documents are designed to satisfy the FAIR principle of being Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, and Reusable, in relation to other dataset documents, and related-but-separate technologies such as data catalogs, HTTP API&amp;rsquo;s, and data package formats Datasets are designed to be stored and distributed on content-addressed (identify-by-hash) systems The dataset document definition is built from a research-first principle, valuing direct interoperability with existing standards over novel definitions or specifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlark Language</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlark_syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlark_syntax/</guid>
      <description>Starlark Syntax Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is about datasets. Transformations are repeatable scripts for generating a dataset. Starlark is a scripting language from Google that feels a lot like python. This package implements skylark as a transformation syntax. Starlark transformations are about as close as one can get to the full power of a programming language as a transformation syntax. Often you need this degree of control to generate a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>