<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qri.io on qri.io</title>
    <link>https://qri.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qri.io on qri.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qri.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministic Querying</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/papers/deterministic_querying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/papers/deterministic_querying/</guid>
      <description>Deterministic Querying for the Distributed Web  Brendan O’Brien
Michael Hucka November 2017 Abstract The current infrastructure that underlies the distribution and processing of data over the Internet has enabled dramatic advances in a wide variety of human activities. Recent trends promoting open data promise even greater benefits as the number and variety of networked datasets grow. However, while current technologies and architectures obviously do work, they also show signs of systemic inefficiencies that impede effective large-scale discovery, distribution, preservation and reuse of datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/questions/</guid>
      <description>Questions What’s a dataset? Datasets are a data structure that is broken up in a way that allows us to link changes between parts of that data structure on a content addressed file system, preserving links in certain ways. With a dataset we have the underlying data, it’s structure which contains the structure &amp;amp; schema of the data.
All datasets have three parts:
 Data - eg: a csv file Metadata - human-oriented description of the data, eg: title, author, date created, category Structure - machine-oriented description of the data, eg: “the third column in this table is a date”  What does Version Control Mean?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>y tho?</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/y_tho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/y_tho/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>