<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>qri</title>
    <link>https://qri.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on qri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qri.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>dataset</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/overview/</guid>
      <description>The word dataset is vague, but it does have a &amp;ldquo;natural&amp;rdquo; meaning to most people. When I think of a &amp;ldquo;dataset&amp;rdquo;, I generally picture a spreadsheet. Spreadsheets are organized into cells, which are an example of a way to structure data. Not all datasets are spreadsheets, but all spreadsheets are datasets.
In contrast, I don&amp;rsquo;t think of a text document as a dataset. But a text document is organized, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quickstart</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/getting_started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/getting_started/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>commit</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/commit/</guid>
      <description> Technical Definition Commit encapsulates information about changes to a dataset in relation to other entries in a given history. Commit is intended to be directly analogous to the concept of a Commit Message in git.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>company</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/company/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/company/</guid>
      <description>qri is a 4 person startup who&amp;rsquo;s been lucky enough to work with a wonderful community of friends. We do work in Brooklyn.
One day we&amp;rsquo;ll get around to writing a proper company description, but if you want to get a hold of us, feel free to email sparkle_pony_2000 at-cymbal qri.io</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>data</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/data/</guid>
      <description> Data stored on qri has a few opinions about datasets: * a dataset is a single file * the root of a dataset is an array * when possible, don&amp;rsquo;t transform or alter data * invalid data is fine, ill-formatted data is not
A Dataset is a single file This restriction might seem silly at first if you&amp;rsquo;re coming from a world of databases.
The root of a Dataset is an Array When possible, don&amp;rsquo;t transform or alter data Invalid data is fine, ill-formated data is not </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>faq</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/faq/</guid>
      <description>Is qri a blockchain? No.
What’s a dataset? Datasets are a data structure that is broken up in a way that allows us to link changes between parts of that data structure on a content addressed file system, preserving links in certain ways. With a dataset we have the underlying data, it’s structure which contains the structure &amp;amp; schema of the data.
All datasets have three parts:
 Data - eg: a csv file Metadata - human-oriented description of the data, eg: title, author, date created, category Structure - machine-oriented description of the data, eg: “the third column in this table is a date”  What does Version Control Mean?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>metadata</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/metadata/</guid>
      <description> Technical Definition Meta contains human-readable metadata about a dataset  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>names</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/names/</guid>
      <description>It’s possible to refer to a dataset in a number of ways. It’s easiest to look at the full definition of a dataset reference, and then show what the “defaults” are to make sense of things. The full definition of a dataset reference is as follows:
dataset_reference = peer_name/dataset_name@/network/hash  an example of that looks like this:
b5/comics@/ipfs/QmejvEPop4D7YUadeGqYWmZxHhLc4JBUCzJJHWMzdcMe2y  In a sentence: b5 is the name of a peer, who has a dataset named comics, and it’s hash on the ipfs network at a point in time was QmejvEPop4D7YUadeGqYWmZxHhLc4JBUCzJJHWMzdcMe2y</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>structure</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/structure/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for tools to keep your data clean, well described, and interoperable with other datasets, structure is where that happens.
Datsaet structure stores everything a computer will need to interpret the data in a dataset. Structure brings expressive tools for making datasets interoperable by storing all necessary details for interpreting data.
Structure is automatically inferred by qri based on the data you provide, making it possible to use qri without having to think about structure until you need to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>transformations</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/transform/</guid>
      <description> Technical Definition Transform is a record of executing a transformation on data. Transforms could be anything from an SQL query, a jupyter notebook, the state of an ETL pipeline, etc, so long as the input is one or more datasets, and the output is a single dataset. Transform should contain all the machine-necessary bits to deterministicly execute the process referenced in &amp;quot;Data&amp;quot;. Consumers of Transforms may be able to produce abstract versions of transformations, a decision left to implementations  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>visconfig</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/viz_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/datasets/viz_config/</guid>
      <description> Technical Definition: VisConfig stores configuration data related to representing a dataset as a visualization  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministic Querying</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/papers/deterministic_querying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/papers/deterministic_querying/</guid>
      <description>Deterministic Querying for the Distributed Web  Brendan O’Brien
Michael Hucka November 2017 Abstract The current infrastructure that underlies the distribution and processing of data over the Internet has enabled dramatic advances in a wide variety of human activities. Recent trends promoting open data promise even greater benefits as the number and variety of networked datasets grow. However, while current technologies and architectures obviously do work, they also show signs of systemic inefficiencies that impede effective large-scale discovery, distribution, preservation and reuse of datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets Are Books, Not Houses</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/datasets_are_books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/datasets_are_books/</guid>
      <description>The world of linked data is built on shaky foundations that prevent a true data commons from emerging. The problem isn’t with the data, but with the way data is linked. Specifically, the way links are addressed.
An address is a uniform, shorthand way of referring to things. Geographic addresses are an obvious example. 1600 Pennsylvania Ave. is the address of the White House. 268 Elizabeth St. is the address of my childhood home.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>