<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>concepts on qri</title>
    <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in concepts on qri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qri.io/docs/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/overview/</guid>
      <description>What is Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;)? Qri is a distributed dataset version control system built with peer-2-peer data exchange. Peers create datasets, which are stored in versions. Qri peers form a distributed network to exchange information about their datasets, which they transmit between each other over the distributed web.
  Datasets are recorded structured data according to a specification that dictates the purpose of each component piece of a dataset. By design, qri can only store datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/dataset/</guid>
      <description>Datasets: Qri&amp;rsquo;s Building Block  #dataset_components { position: relative; margin-bottom: 120px; } .diagram { max-width: 260px; margin: 60px auto; padding: 40px 0; } .descriptions { position: absolute; } .right.descriptions { right: 0; top: 0; text-align: right; } .description { display: block; padding: 5px 8px; margin: 20px 0; border-radius: 6px; background: white; box-shadow: 0 0 3px rgba(0,0,0,0.2); transition: all 0.5s; width: 220px; color: #666; line-height: 1.2em; } .description:hover { box-shadow: 0 5px 6px rgba(0,0,0,0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Addressing</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/content-addressing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/content-addressing/</guid>
      <description>Content Addressing An address is a uniform, shorthand way of referring to things. Geographic addresses are an obvious example. 1600 Pennsylvania Ave. is the address of the White House. 268 Elizabeth St. is the address of my childhood home. These houses are different in size and function, but they are both locations with addresses that adhere to a (relatively) consistent system. Addresses make it easier to refer to places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Storage</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/distributed-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/distributed-storage/</guid>
      <description>Going Distributed Makes Data Free &amp;amp; Dependable Qri doesn’t need a central server to work, instead it&amp;rsquo;s built in a distributed, peer-2-peer architecture that moves data by connecting computers directly. By connecting computers directly, we make storing data on Qri free, because datasets don&amp;rsquo;t have to be stored in the cloud. Your “payment” is the hard drive space to store the data you want to keep. This frees up datasets to get as big as they need to be, and stored wherever makes the most sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPFS → Qri</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/ipfs_to_qri/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/ipfs_to_qri/</guid>
      <description>I know IPFS, what&amp;rsquo;s the deal with Qri? Ooh look at you, smartie pants. You clicked the IPFS link. Assuming you understand the gist of IPFS, this may help connect the dots to how IPFS interacts with Qri.
If you&amp;rsquo;re new to IPFS, no worries. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to understand IPFS to work with Qri. But if you&amp;rsquo;re curious about what all this IPFS talk is about, definitely start with the IPFS docs introduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naming</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/names/</guid>
      <description>Names in Qri It’s possible to refer to a dataset in a number of ways. It’s easiest to look at the full definition of a dataset reference, and then show what the “defaults” are to make sense of things. The full definition of a dataset reference is as follows:
dataset_reference = peer_name/dataset_name@/network/hash  an example of that looks like this:
b5/comics@/ipfs/QmejvEPop4D7YUadeGqYWmZxHhLc4JBUCzJJHWMzdcMe2y  In a sentence: b5 is the name of a peer, who has a dataset named comics, and it’s hash on the ipfs network at a point in time was QmejvEPop4D7YUadeGqYWmZxHhLc4JBUCzJJHWMzdcMe2y</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Source Cascade</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/value_cascade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/value_cascade/</guid>
      <description>Value Cascade A good dataset is as complete and accurate as possible. Good datasets have metadata with a concise yet descriptive title, a description that elaborates, a schema with descriptive details, and so on. When it comes to datasets more detail is better, so long as it&amp;rsquo;s accurate. Because of this, qri provides lots of places to set values. We call those &amp;ldquo;places that might set values&amp;rdquo; sources. There are 4 sources of values in qri:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>