<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on qri</title>
    <link>https://qri.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on qri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 15:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qri.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Qri - Out and Aboot</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/qri_out_and_about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/qri_out_and_about/</guid>
      <description>Just a running catalog of media featuring our project and the team leading it.
&amp;ldquo;Where is the Data Bazaar?&amp;rdquo;
At the AWS Popup Loft in NYC, Brendan presented on the origins of the web, document distribution, Qri, and the data bazaar.
 &amp;ldquo;A Better Mousetrap Podcast&amp;rdquo;
During NYC Open Data Week 2019, Brendan and Rico sat down with Marcos Dinnerstein who runs the podcast A Better Mousetrap to discuss the revolutions in open-source, open data, how Qri got its start and where we&amp;rsquo;re headed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Mousetrap Podcast</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/a_better_mousetrap_podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/a_better_mousetrap_podcast/</guid>
      <description>During NYC Open Data Week, we sat down with Marcos Dinnerstein who runs the A Better Mousetrap podcast to discuss the revolutions in open-source, open data, how Qri got its start and where we&amp;rsquo;re headed. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt:
“In the ‘bazaar’ model of software development, anybody is free to give &amp;amp; take from this code. As we translate this to open data, people are releasing their data, but there’s not as much working together to improve a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Qri</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/introducing_qri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/introducing_qri/</guid>
      <description>I’m delighted to introduce a project a few others and I have been working on for the last few years. It&amp;rsquo;s called Qri (pronounced &amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;. I know, I’m sorry). Qri is about data. Instead of telling you about software, I’d like to start by telling you the story behind why Qri exists.
Two-ish years ago I came across an article in the Washington Post about a group of volunteers getting together for an event at the University of Toronto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Sped Up Unit Test Performance by 10x at Qri</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/unit_test_performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/unit_test_performance/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Dustin, and I work on Qri, helping build our tool for reusable, reproducible, reliable datasets on IPFS. My focus since joining earlier this year has been improving the stability and especially the performance of our application backend. A few months into working on this task, I was especially pained at how slow our entire unit test suite was taking to run - up to nearly 5 minutes on my machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets Are Books, Not Houses</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/datasets_are_books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/datasets_are_books/</guid>
      <description>The world of linked data is built on shaky foundations that prevent a true data commons from emerging. The problem isn’t with the data, but with the way data is linked. Specifically, the way links are addressed.
An address is a uniform, shorthand way of referring to things. Geographic addresses are an obvious example. 1600 Pennsylvania Ave. is the address of the White House. 268 Elizabeth St. is the address of my childhood home.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>