<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorials on qri</title>
    <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorials on qri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python quickstart</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/python_quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/python_quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Python Quickstart  Before you start Install the Python Client Work with qri in a Jupyter Notebook  
1. Before you start Qri has a simple python client that makes it easier to work with qri datasets using the tools you already use&amp;ndash;like pandas and Jupyter.
Since the qri python client is using qri under the hood, for it to work correctly you need to have qri setup and installed before using the python client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI quickstart</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/cli_quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/cli_quickstart/</guid>
      <description>CLI Tutorial (last updated August 8, 2018)
Welcome to the wonderful world of the Qri Command Line Interface. After the first section of this tutorial is the quick start. After following that portion, you will be able to set up your qri repo, check the version of qri you are running, create a new dataset, list your datasets, and export your datasets.
The whole tutorial is divided into six sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlark Transformations</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/skylark_transformations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/skylark_transformations/</guid>
      <description>Starlark Transformations Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is about datasets. A transformation is a repeatable script for generating a dataset. Starlark, formerly &amp;ldquo;Skylark&amp;rdquo;, is a scripting language from Google that feels a lot like python. This package implements skylark as a transformation syntax. Skylark transformations are about as close as one can get to the full power of a programming language as a transformation syntax. Often you need this degree of control to generate a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>