<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorials on qri</title>
    <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorials on qri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlark Examples</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/starlark_examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/starlark_examples/</guid>
      <description>qri and dataset modules In Qri two &amp;ldquo;nonstandard&amp;rdquo; modules specific to qri are available. these modules are not considered part of the standard library project, and are defined in a different repository. They&amp;rsquo;re described here to keep documentation complete:
 qri ds or dataset  Modules  html http math re time xlsx zipfile  
html module can only be used in the download function. You must use the html function to parse an html response, to get a document object that you can traverse</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI quickstart</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/cli_quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/cli_quickstart/</guid>
      <description>CLI Tutorial (last updated Nov 12, 2018, using qri version 0.6.0)
Welcome to the wonderful world of the Qri Command Line Interface. Here we&amp;rsquo;ll get you started with using qri&amp;rsquo;s command-line tools, giving a brief overview of what qri&amp;rsquo;s CLI can do.
The whole tutorial is divided into six sections. The topics are as follows:
 QLI Quickstart
1.1 qri help
1.2 qri version
1.3 qri setup
1.4 qri save</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qri for Git people</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/qri_vs_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/qri_vs_git/</guid>
      <description>Comparing Workflows: Qri, Git, and GitHub By building off a git metaphor, it&amp;rsquo;s easier for someone familiar with Git to understand how Qri is different. Much of this isn&amp;rsquo;t new, but what should be ratified in this RFC is the quality of the explanation. By reading this someone familiar with git should be able to understand the process Qri undertakes to create a dataset. Hopefully this explanation can be copy-pasted into our docs if this RFC is accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlark Transformations</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/starlark_transformations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/starlark_transformations/</guid>
      <description>Starlark Transformations Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is about datasets. A transformation is a repeatable script for generating a dataset. Starlark. This package implements starlark as a transformation syntax. Starlark transformations are about as close as one can get to the full power of a programming language as a transformation syntax. Often you need this degree of control to generate a dataset.
Typical examples of a starlark transformation include:
 combining paginated calls to an API into a single dataset downloading unstructured structured data from the internet to extract  So let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and learn about transforms!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>