<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>qri</title>
    <link>https://qri.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on qri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qri.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Mousetrap Podcast</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/a_better_mousetrap_podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/a_better_mousetrap_podcast/</guid>
      <description>During NYC Open Data Week, we sat down with Marcos Dinnerstein who runs the A Better Mousetrap podcast to discuss the revolutions in open-source, open data, how Qri got its start and where we&amp;rsquo;re headed. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt:
“In the ‘bazaar’ model of software development, anybody is free to give &amp;amp; take from this code. As we translate this to open data, people are releasing their data, but there’s not as much working together to improve a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently-Asked Questions</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/faq/</guid>
      <description>Is qri a blockchain? Nope.
What’s a dataset? Datasets are a data structure that is broken up in a way that allows us to link changes between parts of that data structure on a content addressed file system, preserving links in certain ways. With a dataset we have the underlying data, its structure which contains the structure &amp;amp; schema of the data.
All datasets have at most 6 components. The most important ones are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Qri</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/introducing_qri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/introducing_qri/</guid>
      <description>I’m delighted to introduce a project a few others and I have been working on for the last few years. It&amp;rsquo;s called Qri (pronounced &amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;. I know, I’m sorry). Qri is about data. Instead of telling you about software, I’d like to start by telling you the story behind why Qri exists.
Two-ish years ago I came across an article in the Washington Post about a group of volunteers getting together for an event at the University of Toronto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontend</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/frontend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/frontend/</guid>
      <description>Frontend Screencast Demos We&amp;rsquo;ve filmed screencasts of our teammates demonstrating new features to help you get a feel for qri. Check out some of them below.
Please note! We&amp;rsquo;re improving qri every day. Some of these videos, while still useful, may not reflect the most current state of the app.
Screencast Demo - 0.6.1 (filmed Dec 17, 2018)
What&amp;rsquo;s covered:
 Navigation How to add datasets published by other peers Defining published vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Brendan O&amp;rsquo;Brien - Founder &amp;amp; CEO
Brendan is an open-source software and open data evangelist. He founded Qri during the Data Rescue movement and is responsible for Qri’s code base, road map and growth. He has over a decade of experience in software development, technical due diligence, graphic design and visual arts, having previously founded and led his own successful ventures.
He helped launch Datatogether.org, a network of communities, data scientists and developers dedicated to promoting collective data stewardship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlark Examples</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlark_examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlark_examples/</guid>
      <description>qri and dataset modules In Qri two &amp;ldquo;nonstandard&amp;rdquo; modules specific to qri are available. these modules are not considered part of the standard library project, and are defined in a different repository. They&amp;rsquo;re described here to keep documentation complete:
 qri ds or dataset  Modules  html http math re time xlsx zipfile  
html module can only be used in the download function. You must use the html function to parse an html response, to get a document object that you can traverse</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlark: qri &amp; ds modules</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlib_qri_ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlib_qri_ds/</guid>
      <description>qri and dataset modules In Qri two &amp;ldquo;nonstandard&amp;rdquo; modules specific to qri are available. these modules are not considered part of the standard library project, and are defined in a different repository. They&amp;rsquo;re described here to keep documentation complete:
 qri ds or dataset  
qri module access these methods from the qri module, eg qri.get_config()
 get_config get_secret list_datasets load_dataset_body load_dataset_head  To load:
load(&amp;#34;qri.sky&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;qri&amp;#34;) Function Definitions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlark: standard library</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlib/</guid>
      <description>Starlark Standard Library All qri transforms have access to &amp;ldquo;starlib&amp;rdquo;, a community-driven project to bring a standard library to the starlark programming dialect. Qri needs a standard library, and we thought it might benefit others to structure this library in a reusable way. starlib is admittedly biased towards Qri&amp;rsquo;s needs.
Comments, Suggestions &amp;amp; Pull Requests welcome: https://github.com/qri-io/starlib
Contents    package name description     encoding/base64 base64 defines base64 encoding &amp;amp; decoding functions, often used to represent binary as text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Sped Up Unit Test Performance by 10x at Qri</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/unit_test_performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/unit_test_performance/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Dustin, and I work on Qri, helping build our tool for reusable, reproducible, reliable datasets on IPFS. My focus since joining earlier this year has been improving the stability and especially the performance of our application backend. A few months into working on this task, I was especially pained at how slow our entire unit test suite was taking to run - up to nearly 5 minutes on my machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us  </title>
      <link>https://qri.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>twitter: @qri_io
email: hello [at] qri.io</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI commands</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/cli_commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/cli_commands/</guid>
      <description>Qri CLI command line reference Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is a global dataset version control system on the distributed web.
   Command Description     qri add Add a dataset from another peer   qri body Get the body of a dataset   qri config Get and set local configuration information   qri connect Connect to the distributed web by spinning up a Qri node   qri diff Compare differences between two datasets   qri export Copy datasets to your local filenamesystem   qri get Get elements of qri datasets   qri info Show summarized description of a dataset   qri list Show a list of datasets   qri log Show log of dataset history   qri peers Commands for working with peers   qri publish Make your dataset available on the registry and to your connected peers   qri registry Commands for working with a qri registry   qri remove Remove a dataset from your local repository   qri rename Change the name of a dataset   qri render Execute a template against a dataset   qri save Create a new dataset or save changes to an existing dataset   qri search Search qri   qri setup Initialize qri and IPFS repositories, provision a new qri ID   qri use Select datasets for use with the qri get command   qri validate Show schema validation errors   qri version Print the version number</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI quickstart</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/cli_quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/cli_quickstart/</guid>
      <description>CLI Tutorial (last updated Nov 12, 2018, using qri version 0.6.0)
Welcome to the wonderful world of the Qri Command Line Interface. Here we&amp;rsquo;ll get you started with using qri&amp;rsquo;s command-line tools, giving a brief overview of what qri&amp;rsquo;s CLI can do.
The whole tutorial is divided into six sections. The topics are as follows:
 QLI Quickstart
1.1 qri help
1.2 qri version
1.3 qri setup
1.4 qri save</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Addressing</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/content-addressing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/content-addressing/</guid>
      <description>Content Addressing An address is a uniform, shorthand way of referring to things. Geographic addresses are an obvious example. 1600 Pennsylvania Ave. is the address of the White House. 268 Elizabeth St. is the address of my childhood home. These houses are different in size and function, but they are both locations with addresses that adhere to a (relatively) consistent system. Addresses make it easier to refer to places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataset</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/dataset/</guid>
      <description>Dataset A Dataset is a document for describing &amp;amp; storing structured data. Dataset documents are designed to satisfy the FAIR principle of being Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, and Reusable, in relation to other dataset documents, and related-but-separate technologies such as data catalogs, HTTP API&amp;rsquo;s, and data package formats Datasets are designed to be stored and distributed on content-addressed (identify-by-hash) systems The dataset document definition is built from a research-first principle, valuing direct interoperability with existing standards over novel definitions or specifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/dataset/</guid>
      <description>Datasets: Qri&amp;rsquo;s Building Block  #dataset_components { position: relative; margin-bottom: 120px; } .diagram { max-width: 260px; margin: 60px auto; padding: 40px 0; } .descriptions { position: absolute; } .right.descriptions { right: 0; top: 0; text-align: right; } .description { display: block; padding: 5px 8px; margin: 20px 0; border-radius: 6px; background: white; box-shadow: 0 0 3px rgba(0,0,0,0.2); transition: all 0.5s; width: 220px; color: #666; line-height: 1.2em; } .description:hover { box-shadow: 0 5px 6px rgba(0,0,0,0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Storage</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/distributed-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/distributed-storage/</guid>
      <description>Going Distributed Makes Data Free &amp;amp; Dependable Qri doesn’t need a central server to work, instead it&amp;rsquo;s built in a distributed, peer-2-peer architecture that moves data by connecting computers directly. By connecting computers directly, we make storing data on Qri free, because datasets don&amp;rsquo;t have to be stored in the cloud. Your “payment” is the hard drive space to store the data you want to keep. This frees up datasets to get as big as they need to be, and stored wherever makes the most sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naming</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/names/</guid>
      <description>Names in Qri It’s possible to refer to a dataset in a number of ways. It’s easiest to look at the full definition of a dataset reference, and then show what the “defaults” are to make sense of things. The full definition of a dataset reference is as follows:
dataset_reference = peer_name/dataset_name@/network/hash  an example of that looks like this:
b5/comics@/ipfs/QmejvEPop4D7YUadeGqYWmZxHhLc4JBUCzJJHWMzdcMe2y  In a sentence: b5 is the name of a peer, who has a dataset named comics, and it’s hash on the ipfs network at a point in time was QmejvEPop4D7YUadeGqYWmZxHhLc4JBUCzJJHWMzdcMe2y</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/overview/</guid>
      <description>What is Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;)? Qri is a distributed dataset version control system built with peer-2-peer data exchange. Peers create datasets, which are stored in versions. Qri peers form a distributed network to exchange information about their datasets, which they transmit between each other over the distributed web.
  Datasets are recorded structured data according to a specification that dictates the purpose of each component piece of a dataset. By design, qri can only store datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlark Language</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlark_syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlark_syntax/</guid>
      <description>Starlark Syntax Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is about datasets. Transformations are repeatable scripts for generating a dataset. Starlark is a scripting language from Google that feels a lot like python. This package implements skylark as a transformation syntax. Starlark transformations are about as close as one can get to the full power of a programming language as a transformation syntax. Often you need this degree of control to generate a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starlark Transformations</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/starlark_transformations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/starlark_transformations/</guid>
      <description>Starlark Transformations Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is about datasets. A transformation is a repeatable script for generating a dataset. Starlark. This package implements starlark as a transformation syntax. Starlark transformations are about as close as one can get to the full power of a programming language as a transformation syntax. Often you need this degree of control to generate a dataset.
Typical examples of a starlark transformation include:
 combining paginated calls to an API into a single dataset downloading unstructured structured data from the internet to extract  So let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and learn about transforms!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>terms of service</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/legal/privacy_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/legal/privacy_policy/</guid>
      <description> Privacy Policy </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>terms of service</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/legal/tos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/legal/tos/</guid>
      <description>QRI TERMS OF USE
Qri, Inc. (“Qri,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) welcomes you. We provide you access to our free to use, peer-to-peer network, that allows users to share and collaborate on datasets (the “Network”) via our website at qri.io (the “Website”), subject to the following terms of use (the “Terms of Use”), which may be updated by us from time to time without notice to you.
BY ACCESSING THE WEBSITE AND USING THE NETWORK, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ, UNDERSTOOD, AND AGREE TO BE LEGALLY BOUND BY THESE TERMS OF USE AND OUR PRIVACY POLICY, WHICH IS HEREBY INCORPORATED BY REFERENCE (COLLECTIVELY, THIS “AGREEMENT”).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministic Querying</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/papers/deterministic_querying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/papers/deterministic_querying/</guid>
      <description>Deterministic Querying for the Distributed Web  Brendan O’Brien
Michael Hucka November 2017 Abstract The current infrastructure that underlies the distribution and processing of data over the Internet has enabled dramatic advances in a wide variety of human activities. Recent trends promoting open data promise even greater benefits as the number and variety of networked datasets grow. However, while current technologies and architectures obviously do work, they also show signs of systemic inefficiencies that impede effective large-scale discovery, distribution, preservation and reuse of datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets Are Books, Not Houses</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/datasets_are_books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/datasets_are_books/</guid>
      <description>The world of linked data is built on shaky foundations that prevent a true data commons from emerging. The problem isn’t with the data, but with the way data is linked. Specifically, the way links are addressed.
An address is a uniform, shorthand way of referring to things. Geographic addresses are an obvious example. 1600 Pennsylvania Ave. is the address of the White House. 268 Elizabeth St. is the address of my childhood home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>download</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/download/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/download/</guid>
      <description>Download Qri qri comes in two flavors, an app and a command-line client. If you&#39;re alredy comfortable with the command line, it&#39;s worth checking out the CLI, otherwise, check out the app!
   Qri Desktop Desktop app for interacting with qri datasets on the distributed web.
Currently only available for Mac OS X.
If you&#39;d like to track the status of other installations, check out our progress on github</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>