<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>qri</title>
    <link>https://qri.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on qri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qri.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us  </title>
      <link>https://qri.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>twitter: @qri_io
email: hello [at] qri.io</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently-Asked Questions</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/faq/</guid>
      <description>Is qri a blockchain? Nope.
What’s a dataset? Datasets are a data structure that is broken up in a way that allows us to link changes between parts of that data structure on a content addressed file system, preserving links in certain ways. With a dataset we have the underlying data, its structure which contains the structure &amp;amp; schema of the data.
All datasets have at most 6 components. The most important ones are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python quickstart</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/python_quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/python_quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Python Quickstart  Before you start Install the Python Client Work with qri in a Jupyter Notebook  
1. Before you start Qri has a simple python client that makes it easier to work with qri datasets using the tools you already use&amp;ndash;like pandas and Jupyter.
Since the qri python client is using qri under the hood, for it to work correctly you need to have qri setup and installed before using the python client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI commands</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/cli_commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/cli_commands/</guid>
      <description>Qri CLI command line reference Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is a global dataset version control system on the distributed web.
   Command Description     qri add Add a dataset from another peer   qri body Get the body of a dataset   qri config Get and set local configuration information   qri connect Connect to the distributed web by spinning up a Qri node   qri diff Compare differences between two datasets   qri export Copy datasets to your local filesystem   qri get Get elements of qri datasets   qri info Show summarized description of a dataset   qri list Show a list of datasets   qri log Show log of dataset history   qri new Create a new dataset   qri peers Commands for working with peers   qri registry Commands for working with a qri registry   qri remove Remove a dataset from your local repository   qri rename Change the name of a dataset   qri render Execute a template against a dataset   qri save Save changes to a dataset   qri search Search qri   qri setup Initialize qri and IPFS repositories, provision a new qri ID   qri use Select datasets for use with the qri get command   qri validate Show schema validation errors   qri version Print the version number</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI quickstart</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/cli_quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/cli_quickstart/</guid>
      <description>CLI Tutorial (last updated August 8, 2018)
Welcome to the wonderful world of the Qri Command Line Interface. After the first section of this tutorial is the quick start. After following that portion, you will be able to set up your qri repo, check the version of qri you are running, create a new dataset, list your datasets, and export your datasets.
The whole tutorial is divided into six sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skylark Transformations</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/skylark_transformations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/tutorials/skylark_transformations/</guid>
      <description>Skylark Transformations Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is about datasets. A transformation is a repeatable script for generating a dataset. Starlark, formerly &amp;ldquo;Skylark&amp;rdquo;, is a scripting langauge from Google that feels a lot like python. This package implements skylark as a transformation syntax. Skylark tranformations are about as close as one can get to the full power of a programming language as a transformation syntax. Often you need this degree of control to generate a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Source Cascade</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/value_cascade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/value_cascade/</guid>
      <description>Value Cascade A good dataset is as complete and accruate as possible. Good datasets have metadata with a concise yet descriptive title, a description that elaborates, a schema with descriptive details, and so on. When it comes to datasets more detail is better, so long as it&amp;rsquo;s accurate. Because of this, qri provides lots of places to set values. We call those &amp;ldquo;places that might set values&amp;rdquo; sources. There are 4 sources of values in qri:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>content-addressing</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/content-addressing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/content-addressing/</guid>
      <description>Content Addressing An address is a uniform, shorthand way of referring to things. Geographic addresses are an obvious example. 1600 Pennsylvania Ave. is the address of the White House. 268 Elizabeth St. is the address of my childhood home. These houses are different in size and function, but they are both locations with addresses that adhere to a (relatively) consistent system. Addresses make it easier to refer to places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dataset</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/dataset/</guid>
      <description>Dataset A Dataset is a document for describing &amp;amp; storing structured data. Dataset documents are designed to satisfy the FAIR principle of being Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, and Reusable, in relation to other dataset documents, and related-but-separate technologies such as data catalogs, HTTP API&amp;rsquo;s, and data package formats Datasets are designed to be stored and distributed on content-addressed (identify-by-hash) systems The dataset document definition is built from a research-first principle, valuing direct interoperability with existing standards over novel definitions or specifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>html templates</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/html_templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/html_templates/</guid>
      <description>HTML Templates coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>names</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/names/</guid>
      <description>Names in Qri It’s possible to refer to a dataset in a number of ways. It’s easiest to look at the full definition of a dataset reference, and then show what the “defaults” are to make sense of things. The full definition of a dataset reference is as follows:
dataset_reference = peer_name/dataset_name@/network/hash  an example of that looks like this:
b5/comics@/ipfs/QmejvEPop4D7YUadeGqYWmZxHhLc4JBUCzJJHWMzdcMe2y  In a sentence: b5 is the name of a peer, who has a dataset named comics, and it’s hash on the ipfs network at a point in time was QmejvEPop4D7YUadeGqYWmZxHhLc4JBUCzJJHWMzdcMe2y</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>overview</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/overview/</guid>
      <description>What is Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;)? Qri is a distributed dataset version control system built with peer-2-peer data exchange. Peers create datasets, which are stored in versions. Qri peers form a distributed network to exchange information about their datasets, which they transmit between each other over the distributed web.
Datasets are recorded structured data according to a specification that dictates the purpose of each component piece of a dataset. By design, qri can only store datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>registries</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/registries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/registries/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>skylark function reference</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/sylark_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/sylark_functions/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>starlark syntax</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/skylark_syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/skylark_syntax/</guid>
      <description>Starlark Syntax Qri (&amp;ldquo;query&amp;rdquo;) is about datasets. Transformions are repeatable scripts for generating a dataset. Starlark is a scripting langauge from Google that feels a lot like python. This package implements skylark as a transformation syntax. Starlark tranformations are about as close as one can get to the full power of a programming language as a transformation syntax. Often you need this degree of control to generate a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>starlib reference</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/reference/starlib/</guid>
      <description>Starlark Standard Library Modules  qri ds or dataset http html time xlsx  
qri module you can access these methods from the qri module, eg qri.get_config()
 get_config get_secret list_datasets load_dataset_body load_dataset_head  To load:
load(&amp;#34;qri.sky&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;qri&amp;#34;) Function Definitions: 
get_config qri.get_config(key)
returns the value of a config variable, declared in the dataset file:
# in the dataset.yaml file:transform:scriptpath:transform.skyconfig:key:value 
get_secret qri.get_secret(key)
returns the value of a secrets variable, declared in the dataset file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>terms of service</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/legal/privacy_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/legal/privacy_policy/</guid>
      <description> Privacy Policy </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>terms of service</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/legal/tos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/legal/tos/</guid>
      <description>QRI TERMS OF USE
Qri, Inc. (“Qri,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) welcomes you. We provide you access to our free to use, peer-to-peer network, that allows users to share and collaborate on datasets (the “Network”) via our website at qri.io (the “Website”), subject to the following terms of use (the “Terms of Use”), which may be updated by us from time to time without notice to you.
BY ACCESSING THE WEBSITE AND USING THE NETWORK, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ, UNDERSTOOD, AND AGREE TO BE LEGALLY BOUND BY THESE TERMS OF USE AND OUR PRIVACY POLICY, WHICH IS HEREBY INCORPORATED BY REFERENCE (COLLECTIVELY, THIS “AGREEMENT”).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>version control</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/version_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/docs/concepts/version_control/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deterministic Querying</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/papers/deterministic_querying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/papers/deterministic_querying/</guid>
      <description>Deterministic Querying for the Distributed Web  Brendan O’Brien
Michael Hucka November 2017 Abstract The current infrastructure that underlies the distribution and processing of data over the Internet has enabled dramatic advances in a wide variety of human activities. Recent trends promoting open data promise even greater benefits as the number and variety of networked datasets grow. However, while current technologies and architectures obviously do work, they also show signs of systemic inefficiencies that impede effective large-scale discovery, distribution, preservation and reuse of datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets Are Books, Not Houses</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/blog/datasets_are_books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/blog/datasets_are_books/</guid>
      <description>The world of linked data is built on shaky foundations that prevent a true data commons from emerging. The problem isn’t with the data, but with the way data is linked. Specifically, the way links are addressed.
An address is a uniform, shorthand way of referring to things. Geographic addresses are an obvious example. 1600 Pennsylvania Ave. is the address of the White House. 268 Elizabeth St. is the address of my childhood home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>download</title>
      <link>https://qri.io/download/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qri.io/download/</guid>
      <description>Download Qri qri comes in two flavors, an app and a command-line client. If you&#39;re alredy comfortable with the command line, it&#39;s worth checking out the CLI, otherwise, check out the app!
   Qri Desktop Desktop app for interacting with qri datasets on the distributed web.
Currently only available for Mac OS X.
If you&#39;d like to track the status of other installations, check out our progress on github</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>